when I remodeled these houses do you
know what my main goal was to make my
tenants happy oh wow granite countertops
Total Electric big sinks hardwood
cabinets I've only had one tenant loved
it so much she lived here until she died
what did this place cost I've bought
more rental houses for free than anybody
you know and I was making over $7,000 a
month off of rent people think there's
some gimmick to it no if you want to
make money buy a bucket and go in there
and fix it
yourself Jess Joe you flew me all the
way from Canada why am I here today well
look at this wonderful Little Gym
man a lot of people want to see the
inside of my houses I own a whole lot
everybody knows I'm a real estate
investor this is a house that I remodel
with my own two hands but more
importantly design with my own two hands
I have a saying when I renovate anything
and that's renovate right most people go
with the cheapest option available every
time I go for an option that has an
intentional end when I remind mod these
houses do you know what my main goal was
to make my tenants happy have you ever
heard any investor say that was their
chief goal or aim no it's all about
money yet I'm a wildly successful real
estate investor so why am I so worried
about my tenants happiness well first of
all I choose people over profits every
time and I don't give if I make no money
I'm not going to do somebody dirty
that's how I am personally you know I've
followed this saying to a tune of paper
millions in this case I want the people
to be happy my goal with these is to
have the power B under $100 I want the
person that lives in this house to live
here forever one why because they'll be
happy and two anytime somebody moves out
I lose $5,000 how's that well you got to
think if they move out at the end of the
month then you have the other month to
get it fixed up renovated cleaned
whatever you have to do you lose one
whole month then if you list it for rent
they don't move in at the start of the
month you usually lose the second month
so between two months worth of rent and
the utilities you have to get turned on
in your name and the little bit of work
you have to do you're going to lose
about $5,000 every time and that's best
case scenario if it rents immediately so
why is $5,000 a lot if you're following
the Burr method how much do you expect
to clear per door three 400 bucks $400
is really good you lose your entire
Year's profit if one person moves out
you never read that in a book nowhere
did you no I did not this is common
sense to me a lot of the ideas I have
are very original and unique because
I've never read a book and I've never
listened to a podcast I just think about
this is what I come up with now how did
I achieve this aim of getting my tenants
to have under $100 power bill in the
south on a total electric home I have no
clue we do it notice look at all the
other roofs around do you see another
metal roof anywhere no why am I the only
person with the metal roof
here oh wow what is the first thing you
notice when you walk in vaed ceilings
yeah feels very spacious vaed ceilings
do you like that yeah okay people like
it my first goal number two physics what
does hot air do heat rises okay so how
does it feel down here here it's nice
and cool we have air vents right there
what does cold air do goes down pushes
the hot air up okay so in the main
living area the heart of the home we
have literally created using physics a
place for the heat to go so it feels
cooler in the home because people are
happier when it's more comfortable and
when it's cooler down here you'll run
that AC less which will be more energy
efficient your power bill will be lower
this gives them reasons to stay instead
of reasons to leave yeah next thing
solid floring solid flooring ceramic
tile black grout will not scratch it
will not burn unless you drop an anvil
on it it will not break it is cold do
you notice that yeah it is so this is a
slab which means it's touching the Earth
and the Earth is cold and this puts heat
back into the ground it literally draws
it out of the house that's not great
during the winter but that's only 3
months in Georgia the rest of the time
we want this sucking all the heat
because it's cooler in the house and you
run your AC less absolutely all of these
homes started out as a two-bedroom one
bath with a single car garage over there
this was not here it had no laundry I
figured out a place to put a laundry
room in here that's not easy because it
has to have a drain line and a water
source stackable washer and dryer fits
right here what is this water heater
that's a tankless electric water heater
do you think it's cheaper than the other
one no it's far more expensive than a
regular water heater but it only
produces hot water when you're using it
it does not heat water all day long
think about the percentage of the day
you actually are actively using hot
water versus the time it's heated also I
don't have room in here it's 926 ft it
makes it easier to rent and they never
leave I went through a lot of trouble to
put this here granite countertops boom
boom granite countertops this is 926
Square F feet with an open floor plane
where would you put a dining room table
here there's not space no there's not
space but guess what I thought about
that M so I put an eat at bar right here
where you literally could put parent one
parent two child
child even a third if you needed to yeah
you could easily sit five people here do
you like the granite countertops yeah
solid quality lost makes people happy
will never have to be replaced y Total
Electric garbage disposal big sinks
hardwood cabinets these are very
expensive cabinets there's no particle
board in there soft clo hinges if you
want somebody to take care of something
you have to give them a quality product
and through my branding and messaging
that I put in this house is I take very
good care of my I expect you to also and
when you have a quality product you can
charge a quality price and also attract
a quality person now if you're investing
longterm like I am this is what you want
to do I don't have a service call on
almost any of my houses why this is
rewired it's replumbed it has a new roof
it has new cabinets if anything breaks
in here it's fall yeah I make that very
clear up front I'm going to give you a
great home and I expect you to take
great care of it here's the master suite
that we added out of a single car garage
oh wow there's a third bedroom and a
second bathroom so who pays all the
bills at a house Mom Dad the parents and
where do they generally stay in the
master bedroom so that's where we are
that means I want them to be the
happiest in the house so you know what
they get in the master bedroom good siiz
bedroom huge bathroom a walk-in closet
you're not going to get a master suite
like this in this price range I have set
my house apart for the competition I
have granite countertops I have wall
toall tile you have a master suite with
a walk-in closet you have Granite
kitchen countertops you have an eatat
bar you have a total electric home with
a tankless electric water heater and
guess what I spent an extra $4,000 to
foam insulate every house I have why
well one it keeps the heat out of the
attic the duct work in the Attic is 60
Dees cooler what does that do to the
life of your unit lives longer what does
that do to the power bill opposite
produces it what does it do to the
entire home system to keep a massive
amount of heat out of it it makes it
last longer combined with the metal roof
this is a massive Energy savings and I
have literally achieved my goal of
having my tenants have less than a $100
a month power bill in this house and the
lady that lived here loved it so much
she lived here until she died I've only
had one
tenant huge yard wow lots of room look
at the
backyard let's talk some numbers what
did this place cost
$112,000 wow and how long ago did you
buy this I think about 6 years ago guess
how much it's renting for $1,200 a month
that's a one 1% a month return off the
initial purchase price but what's it
worth one 75 140 to 150 what do I have
in it about $660,000 I did well probably
less I did all of the work myself I did
not pay myself a dime I did all this
work myself the plum and I roughed it in
why cuz I'm investing I could have paid
myself I don't need that money I put it
in here and what I did is I left all of
my investment in my properties and then
what I did is I took the rent that was
generated from them and I invested it I
did not refinance anything what did I do
I took 100% of the rent and kept
reinvesting it I've bought more rental
houses for free than anybody you know
wow check this out bro I paid $112,000
for this house it's rented for 1,200
bucks a month if you have it rented for
1,200 bucks a month how many months will
it take you before you can buy another
$122,000 house with one rental 10 months
after about 3 years of buying rentals I
had eight paid for properties owed no
money and I was making over $7,000 a
month off of rent I was buying these
houses for less than $35,000 so every
five months I could buy another one yeah
I had a construction company and we were
working on this Friday Saturday and
pretty soon it turned into all we did
was work on my houses and then we
started flipping houses I mean and all
we did was come in here and work and
people think there's some gimmick to it
no if you want to make money buy a
bucket and go in there and fix it
yourself it's the most fail safe way to
do it you don't have to have a whole lot
of money you just have to have a little
bit of work ethic I don't know why
people are reading books and podcasts if
you want to get in a real estate get in
a real estate save some money up and buy
a house like this what will you have at
the end property source of income this
is one thing I try and put in
everybody's head that that they don't
understand skill at the end of this you
would know so much about the investing
game at the end of this you would know
how to acquire an off-market property
how to save $122,000 how to renovate a
house how to work with subcontractors
how to lease out a property how to
manage a property how to run a
background just in one transaction and
then with that you go to the next one
that's what I'm saying every time I did
this I got better and better and better
at every aspect of this game and now I
understand this top to bottom all the
way around and I can walk the dog on
this anywhere I go in the world why
because I properly equipped myself I
didn't hire nobody to do nothing I
figured it yeah cuz how can you manage
somebody if you don't know how to do it
yourself yeah for sure